Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Education for Liberation Network Archived Website, Mar 14, 2012- ongoing; Education for Liberation Network
  The Education for Liberation Network, established in 1999, is a national coalition of teachers, community activists, researchers, youth and parents who educate low-income youth and youth of color to work for social justice by taking action in local communities to empower students. The network primarily functions as a listserv, but also contains a database of education materials, and projects page.
  Education and society.
- Education for Peace in Iraq Center Archived Website, Dec 3, 2008- ongoing; Education for Peace in Iraq Center
  Founded in 1998, EPIC: Promoting a Free and Secure Iraq works to improve human rights and humanitarian conditions in Iraq. EPIC works through educational programs and advocacy initiatives to stabilize Iraq by supporting Iraqi efforts to advance peace and development on the ground. The website contains news and a blog.
  Human rights |z Iraq.; Iraq War, 2003-2011.; Iraq |x Social conditions |y 21st century.
- Education Notes Online Archived Website, May 11, 2010- ongoing; Education Notes Online
  Education Notes provides news on current education issues and organizing activities for fighting for public education in cities throughout the United States. Education Notes was founded in 1996 as a monthly newsletter published by Norm Scott that transformed into a blog in 2006.
  United Federation of Teachers.; Charter schools |z New York (State) |z New York.; Charter schools |z United States.; Education |z New York (State) |z New York.; Education |z United States.; Educational change |z New York (State) |z New York.; Teachers' unions |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Electronic Frontier Foundation Archived Website, Apr 17, 2010- ongoing; Electronic Frontier Foundation
  The Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF), founded in 1990, is a civil liberties group that defends users’ rights in the digital world. EFF uses lawyers, policy analysts, activists, and technologists on behalf of consumers and the general public. EFF fights for freedom primarily in the courts, bringing and defending lawsuits and mobilizations. In addition to advising policymakers, EFF educates the press and public. EFF’s issues are defending free speech, privacy, innovation, and consumer rights. The website also contains a blog and campaign page.
- Encyclopedia of Trotskyism On-Line (ETOL) Archived Website, Dec 9, 2008- ongoing; Encyclopedia of Trotskyism On-Line (ETOL)
  Encyclopedia of Trotskyism On-Line (ETOL) is a resource for the study of the international Trotskyist movement. It includes a "tree" of U.S. Trotskyist organizations, a list of pseudonyms, historical documents, and other materials.
  Communism.; Socialism.; Trotskyism |z United States.; Trotskyism.
- Environmental News Network Archived Website, Sep 15, 2012- ongoing; Environmental News Network
  Environmental News Network (ENN), established in 1997, is a news wire dedicated to presenting news on worldwide environmental issues and promotes discussion between readers. In addition to publishing the website, they offer rss feeds and distribute a daily e-newsletter to 36,000 environmental readers. The website features sections on environmental policy, climate, energy, green building, pollution, ecosystems, wildlife, agriculture, and science and technology. The website also features original news stories and a blog.
  Environmentalism.; News web sites |z United States.
- Equal Justice USA Archived Website, Apr 7, 2012- ongoing; Equal Justice USA
  Equal Justice USA, founded in 1990, is a national, grassroots organization working to build a criminal justice system that is fair, effective, and humane, starting with repealing the death penalty, increasing services for families of homicide victims, and refocusing resources towards criminal justice policies that reduce crime and support victims. They partner with state organizations to provide training and leadership development, and free consulting to build grassroots campaign. The website contains action alerts and news.
  Capital punishment.; Prisoners |x Civil rights.
- Eugene V. Debs Foundation Archived Website, Aug 10, 2010- ongoing; Eugene V. Debs Foundation.
  The Eugene V. Debs Foundation was founded in 1962 to preserve the Debs home and open it as a museum for the public, as well as act as a repository for Debs’ papers and other artifacts. The Foundation also administers an award yearly to an individual that embodies "the spirit of progressivism, humanitarianism, and social criticism by Eugene V. Debs." The website also contains their biannual newsletter, a biography of Debs, information about the museum, and their essay contest.
  Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926 |x Museums.; Socialists |z United States.
- Experimental Party Disinformation Center Archived Website, May 10, 2008 - Nov 19, 2008; Experimental Party Disinformation Center.
  Experimental Party Disinformation Center: Anarchic Entertainment for the Nation!The Experimental Party is an initiative of the "US Department of Art and Technology." A website active in 2004-2005 concerned with protesting the nomination, election, and inauguration of George W. Bush as President of the United States.
  Anarchists |z United States.; Presidents |z United States |x Election |y 2004.
- F (Foreclose) the Banks Archived Website, Mar 25, 2013-Jun 25, 2013; F (Foreclose) the Banks
  F (Foreclose) the Banks, is an action campaign by Occupy Wall Street activists, which is working to end corporate and bank power in the United States. The website contains information on action campaigns and informational materials.
  Social responsibility in banking.
- Fairness & Accuracy in Reporting Archived Website, Mar 8, 2010- ongoing; Fairness & Accuracy in Reporting (Organization).
  FAIR (Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting), a national media watch group, has been offering criticism of media bias and censorship since 1986. FAIR advocates greater diversity in the press, structural reform in the media, and works to expose neglected news stories. FAIR publishes Extra!, a magazine of media criticism, and produces the weekly radio program CounterSpin. In addition, they have a listserv through which they distribute regular action alerts to their international network of activists.
  Alternative mass media |z United States.; Mass media criticism |z United States.
- FairVote.org Archived Website, Sep 14, 2010- ongoing; Fair Vote: The Center for Voting and Democracy
  FairVote is an organization that acts to reform the elections process to achieve universal access to participation, a national popular vote for president, constitutionally protected right to vote, universal voter registration, instant runoff voting, and proportional voting. To achieve these goals, FairVote acts as a traditional think tank through research, analysis, educational resources and conferences, and also engages with leading reformers, thought leaders and the media to turn new ideas into widely accepted policy options.
  Elections |z United States.; Proportional representation |z United States; Voting--United States
- FedCURE Archived Website, Mar 8, 2012- ongoing; FedCURE
  Federal CURE, Inc (FedCURE) works as an advocate for the federal inmate population. FedCURE also raises awareness of the issues confronted by the federal inmate population. Their work includes reinstating parole; increasing good time allowances; providing for compassionate releases; restoring PELL grants; and creating opportunities for successful reentry into the community, for all federal offenders; and promoting a system that incarcerates fewer people and provides humane conditions for those who are incarcerated or under post-incarceration supervision via parole or supervised release. The website contains news postings, action alerts, and a chapters list.
  Prisoners |x Civil rights |z United States.
- Federal Bureau of Investigation - Guantanamo Bay Investigation Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation.
  Contains a survey of 493 Federal Bureau of Investigation personnel asking whether they observed aggressive mistreatment, interrogations or interview techniques at the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners of war, American.; Torture |z United States.
- Fellowship of Reconciliation Archived Website, May 8, 2008-ongoing; Fellowship of Reconciliation (U.S.).
  Founded in 1915, The Fellowship of Reconciliation (FOR) holds programs and educational projects concerned with domestic and international peace and justice, nonviolent alternatives to conflict, and the rights of conscience in opposition to warfare. FOR promotes nonviolence and has members from many religious and ethnic traditions. It is a part of the International Fellowship of Reconciliation (IFOR), which has affiliates in over 40 countries. The website contains information on campaigns, events, and delegations. The website also has a multimedia page and a blog.
  Pacifism--United States.; Peace movements |z United States.
- FeministCampus.org Archived Website, Jul 9, 2011- ongoing; Feminist Majority Foundation
  FeministCampus.org was created by the Feminist Majority Foundation (FMF) to inform young feminists on college campuses about threats to abortion access, women’s rights, affirmative action, and lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender rights. FMF works with students on college campuses to effect change at the grassroots, national, and global levels. The Campus Program is built upon FMF’s philosophy that the most effective activism is informed activism, or study to action. Their program provides progressive students with opportunities to learn about feminist issues, develop their leadership and organizing skills, and connect with the larger pro-choice and feminist movements.
  Endowments.; Women college students--Political activity.
- Feministe Archived Website, May 4, 2012- ongoing; Feministe
  Feministe is a feminist blog. The website features multiple different authors and guest-bloggers. The website features blog posts and analysis on race, women’s health, parenthood, politics, a book club, and other articles on feminist issues. The website also promotes its commenting community.
  Feminism.
- Ferguson Action Archived Website, Dec 10, 2014-ongoing; Ferguson Action.
  Website documenting the Black Lives Matter movement following the police murders of Mike Brown and Eric Garner in 2014. The website includes listings for actions, movement demands, and resources.
  Black power.; Grand jury |z United States.; Police brutality.
- Ferguson National Response Network, Dec 10, 2014-ongoing; Ferguson National Response Network.
  This site was originally created to list actions across the United States organized in response to the Ferguson, MO grand jury decision in the killing of unarmed African-American teenager Mike Brown in 2014. The website later expanded to list other events pertaining to police brutality, racial injustice, and the Black Lives Matter movement.
- Fifth Avenue Committee Archived Website, Mar 6, 2012 - ongoing; Fifth Avenue Committee
  Fifth Avenue Committee, Inc. (FAC), established in 1978, is a community organization in South Brooklyn that advances economic and social justice. FAC develops and manages affordable housing and community facilities, creates economic opportunities and ensures access to economic stability, organizes residents and workers, offers student-centered adult education, and combats displacement caused by gentrification. The website contains information on their programming and event listings.
  Community organization.; Low-income housing.
- Fight For The Future Archived Website, Apr 23, 2012- ongoing; Fight for the Future
  Fight for the Future is a non-profit that helps organize strikes and petitions against web censorship. The website features petitions against the SOPA and PIPA censorship bills and other petitions and other campaigns.
  Intellectual property.
- Fight Imperialism Stand Together Archived Website, Aug 1, 2009-Jun 24, 2013; Fight Imperialism Stand Together.
  Fight Imperialism Stand Together (FIST) is a national youth revolutionary group affiliated with the Workers World Party, a Marxist-Leninist communist organization of Trotskyist provenance. The organization advocates for the equality of race, sex, orientation, and the working class. The website contains news listings and their blog. The site last updated in 2011.
  Communism |z United States.; Socialism and youth |z United States.; Trotskyism |z United States.
- Fighting Bob Archived Website, Jan 8, 2012- ongoing; Fighting Bob
  Fighting Bob, founded in 2003, is an online opinion magazine named for Robert La Follette (1855–1925), a populist governor, U.S. Senator, and presidential candidate from Wisconsin who founded the Progressive Party. The website publishes opinion articles on mostly Wisconsin issues not covered by mainstream media. The editor is Ed Garvey.
  Electronic journals |z United States.; Social justice--Wisconsin.; Social justice.
- FirstGameWorld.Com: Occupy Wall Street Archived Website, Oct 25, 2011-Nov 28, 2011; FirstGameWorld.com
  Website that aggregates news articles about Occupy Wall Street
- First Voices Indigenous Radio (FVIR) Archived Website, May 22, 2011- ongoing; First Voices Indigenous Radio
  First Voices Indigenous Radio: A Voice for Indigenous Issues, Concerns, Cultures and Customs (FVIR), is a weekly radio program broadcast on WBAI FM (New York, N.Y.) that gives a voice to Indigenous peoples worldwide (with a focus on North American Indigenous groups) to share their experiences, perspectives, and struggles. FVIR’s purpose is to ensure the continuance and survival of Indigenous cultures and Nations through. FVIR also works to educate by breaking down stereotypes. The program, hosted by Tiokasin Ghosthorse, airs on Thursday mornings at 9 AM.
  Alternative radio broadcasting |z United States.; Indians of North America.
- Flood Wall Street Archived Website, Flood Wall Street.
  Flood Wall Street was organized as a response to the call for non- violent direct action following the People's Climate March in 2014. On September 22nd, 2014, hundreds of people conducted a sit-in on Broadway in lower Manhattan, resulting in the arrest of over 100 people. The action sought to hold corporations and banks accountable for their role in creating the climate crisis.
  Climate change.; Direct action |z United States.; Environmental justice.; Environmentalism |z New York (State) |z New York.
- FOIA Post (2007): Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions -- August 2007 Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States Department of Justice. Office of Information Policy.
  Contains summaries of Federal court decisions pertaining to the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp that were received by the Office or Information Policy during the month of August 2007.
  Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Law and legislation |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.; Military interrogation--United States--Evaluation.; Torture |z United States.
- FOIA Post (2009): Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions -- January 2009 Archived Website, Nov 20, 2009-Nov 30, 2010; United States. Dept of Justice. Office of Information Policy.
  Contains summaries of [Federal] court decisions pertaining to the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp that were received by Office of Information Policy during the month of January 2009.
  Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Law and legislation.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners of war, American.; Torture |z United States.
- Foreclosure Fraud Archived Website, Mar 6, 2012 - ongoing; Foreclosure Fraud
  4closure Fraud is a website designed to help people fight foreclosure through awareness and legal action. The website contains depositions, information on foreclosure laws, a news blog, a links page, and the website’s radio show.
  Foreclosure. Mortgages. Social responsibility in banking.
- FrackAction.com Archived Website, Jul 6, 2011- ongoing; FrackAction.com
  Frack Action is an action group that campaigns against the hydraulic fracturing (fracking). Fracking is the process of initiating and subsequently propagating a fracture in a rock layer, by means of a pressurized fluid, in order to release petroleum, natural gas, coal seam gas, or other substances for extraction. Frack Action works to raise awareness, expose false claims of the gas industry, and mobilize to protect the environment and public health from the environmental consequences of fracking.
  Environmentalism.; Hydraulic fracturing.
- Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt Institute Archived Website, Nov 27, 2012- ongoing; Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt Institute
  The Roosevelt Institute, founded in 1987, is a progressive non-profit organization devoted to carrying forward the legacy and values of Franklin and Eleanor Roosevelt by developing ideas and leadership to promote the United States’ health and security. The website features their Four Freedoms think tank and their Campus Network and Pipeline campaigns, which works to create young progressive leaders that promote the Institute’s values. The website also features information on the FDR presidential library and their Next New Deal blog.
- Free Culture Foundation Archived Website, Jul 10, 2013-Oct 9, 2014; Free Culture Foundation
  The Free Culture Foundation, formerly Students for Free Culture (found in Tamiment’s Education and Student Movements web archive), is an organization with the goal to end the private ownership over media, ideas, and technology; promote the advancement of free software, formats, and works; raise consciousness of intellectual property; and defend against privacy threats. The organization works through supporting local and student chapters, providing educational resources, organizing direct action campaigns, and sponsoring events and other projects. The website contains a blog, projects, volunteering opportunities, and resources.
- Freedom Road Socialist Organization Archived Website, Feb 27, 2010- ongoing; Fight Imperialism Stand Together.
  Freedom Road Socialist Organization/Organicion Socialista del Camino Para la Libertad (FRSO/OSCL) was founded in 1985 when two small organizations, Proletarian Unity League (PUL) and the Revolutionary Workers Headquarters (RWH) merged. They are a network of revolutionary organizers that work to fight white supremacist capitalism. They work in the Black and Chicano movements and various immigrants’ struggles, and in labor unions, workers centers and labor/community groups and coalitions. The website contains information on their platform and news and analysis.
  Socialism |z United States.; Socialist parties |z United States.
- Freedom Socialist Party Archived Website, Feb 7, 2007- ongoing; Freedom Socialist Party (U.S.).
  The Freedom Socialist Party (FSP) was founded in 1966 by former members of the Socialist Workers Party. The party is a revolutionary, socialist feminist organization, dedicated to the replacement of capitalist rule by a genuine workers’ democracy that will guarantee full economic, social, political, and legal equality to women, people of color, gays, and all who are exploited, oppressed, and repelled by imperialism. The website contains their publication, Freedom Socialist, their platform, and information on their affiliates and chapters.
  Feminism |z United States.; Socialism |z United States.
- Freegan.info Archived Website, Jul 27, 2009- ongoing; Freegan.Info
  The Freegan.info website was created in 2003 as a project of the Activism Center at Wetlands Preserve in New York City. The website has evolved to offer a monthly calendar of local freegan skill share, discussion, a dumpster directory, links page, and social events. The website also works to support and connect the New York City branch with other Freegan groups throughout the world. Freeganism is an anti-consumerist lifestyle by people who employ alternative strategies for living based on limited participation in the conventional economy and minimal consumption of resources.
  Anarchism |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Free Press Archived Website, Feb 3, 2012- ongoing; Free Press
  Free Press is a national, nonpartisan, nonprofit organization working to reform the media. Through education, organizing and advocacy, they promote diverse and independent media ownership, strong public media, and universal access to communications. Free Press was launched in late 2002 by media scholar Robert W. McChesney and Josh Silver. As of 2012 Free Press has nearly half a million activists and members and a full-time staff of more than 40. The website contains information on campaigns, education and research, and has related news content.
  Freedom of speech |z United States.; Freedom of the press |z United States; Mass media criticism.
- Free Speech TV Archived Website, Aug 28, 2009- ongoing; Free Speech TV.
  Free Speech TV, launched in 1995, is an independent, publicly-supported TV multi platform digital media service that works to build an equitable and sustainable society. In 2000, Free Speech TV launched the first national progressive television network when it was awarded a full-time satellite channel on DISH Network as a result of an FCC policy to set aside 4% of satellite channels for public interest channels. Free Speech TV is based in Denver, CO and is produced by Public Communicators Inc., founded in 1974. Promoting voices and perspectives under-represented in the media, Free Speech TV broadcasts independently-produced programs addressing social, political, cultural, and environmental issues, and produced the SourceCode series (2004-2007).
  Television broadcasting--United States.
- Free The Media Archived Website, Jul 24, 2010-Oct 22, 2013; Free The Media!
  Free the Media is an autonomous network and cultural think tank whose purpose is to reclaim public space on the net and preserve free speech, privacy and access for all The website is made up of artists, activists, and technologists working collectively to create self-sustainable infrastructures and open source software tools that enable access and the free exchange of information in the digital world. The website also is a platform for exchange of ideas and issues that are put into action through live events and actions.
  Freedom of information.; Internet |x Political aspects.; Research institutes--Computer networks; World Wide Web |x Political aspects.
- Free University New York City Archived Website, Sep 13, 2012- ongoing; Free University
  The Free University of New York City, first established May 2012, is an radical education movement that offers free education in open spaces in New York City. Their aim is to reform education to make it more accessible to those who cannot afford higher education. They view their education program as a direct action against the current, capitalist education system and work to democratize and radicalize education. The website contains information on their latest actions, their working group, and multimedia.
  Education reform.
- Friends of the Earth International Archived Website, Jul 6, 2013 - ongoing; Friends of the Earth International.